It's finally done.
Our new house is complete.
Looking at it now, it really is huge.
Keep on digging!
We're going to add a cellar
You want me to keep going?
We need big support beams, too!
Here comes the swing. Fore!
Yup.
I had an inkling while working
that it would turn out like this, but still.
And we helped out with the design.
Right?
Yup.
We also made sure that
the requests of the future residents
were all addressed during construction.
I'm a resident too, you know.
It wouldn't feel right if you didn't have
the nicest house here, Hiraku!
Let's tour the interior.
The structure inside looks a lot like
the house you live in, Lea.
Right now we're in the main hall.
We designed it so that everyone could
gather here and chat or hang out.
And this here is your room, Hiraku.
I like it.
And opposite your room
across the main hall is...
the dining room.
There's a kitchen in the back.
We even set up more stoves outside.
So this is the cellar, huh?
This will be great for storing
food and firewood.
I was hoping for my own room!
It was getting crowded with
all the people we have now.
It looks like you guys
really like your rooms.
Yeah!
So what's this room over here?
This one has a bolt lock for some reason.
Why did they put one here?
I'll pretend I didn't see that.
It's really exciting to finally see
our new house like this.
Ah, I love everything about it.
Looking up at that tree from here
makes it feel like it's watching over us.
Yeah, this is a really great house.
Thank you very much.
After you've spent the winter here, if you
feel any part of the house is unsatisfactory
please let me know so that we may fix it.
Got it.
There we go.
In addition to my God statue, I decided
to make some statues of my dogs.
I put them in front of the entrance
to the new house.
Yeah, this is shaping up pretty nicely.
Farming Life in Another World
When you open your eyes and see
that pure white light, the story begins
Stepping forth into a new world,
what kind of flowers will we make bloom?
Even if it's cloudy,
even if we get dirty from a puddle
We continue on
There's a future we can't imagine
waiting for us, I'm sure of it
Meeting, meeting, and connecting
If you smile,
everyone around you will smile too
Let's plant a small seed and nurture it
One day it'll become a large flower
Turn regrets and failures into fuel
So that you're overflowing with colorful happiness
We'll join hands and share
Spread across the world, Flower Ring
Hm.
This looks like all the main ingredients.
Ah, I overdid it out there
and now I'm starving.
What are we eating today?
I going to try and see if I can manage to make
a new dish we haven't tried yet.
Something new?
Yeah.
It's called curry.
Huh, I've never heard of that.
You're going to try to make it?
Does that mean that this curry is
a difficult dish to make?
Well, it can be easy to make,
but mastering the dish takes a lot of work.
Usually, you'd just add roux to the pot
and cook it like that.
Lu?!
So that's the kind of stuff you're into?!
You savage!
What are you talking about?
Wow.
I didn't realize that you'd planted
all these crop fields, too!
Yeah, I've been working at it little by little.
There are a lot of plants here I don't recognize.
Yup.
That's because there are a lot of plants here
that normally can't grow in climates
with any snowfall.
With the almighty farming tool,
I can grow plants that are
really sensitive to seasonal weather.
The almighty farming tool really does it all.
Okay, lets harvest the spices
we're going to need for the curry.
First up is cumin.
That's a cute sounding name.
It looks like it's already dried out.
Cumin
After the flower has already bloomed,
the seed that gets left behind
makes for a good spice.
It's the spice that's most responsible
for curry's aroma.
What a peculiar smell.
Turmeric
Next up is turmeric.
It's the main ingredient
that gives curry its color.
The part we care about is the root,
but the part that grows
above ground is pretty huge.
We dry out the part that grows
underground and use that.
I ended up asking the girls
to dry them out for me.
Dry out, dry out. Become dry.
Magic really is handy.
Coriander
And next is coriander.
We grind the seeds up into powder
and use them.
This one has a nice and fresh,
fruit-like aroma.
Yeah.
The green leaves up top are called cilantro.
Cilantro
These have a potent aroma.
Do you want to eat this?
Well, I guess we like different flavors.
Did you see that?
Yeah.
That's a plant capable of
driving off inferno wolves.
I think that one will be worth researching.
Next, we have black pepper.
And cayenne peppers.
Great. These are all the spices I'll need.
Wait.
Hold on.
I've heard that girls think guys who make
their own curry from scratch,
starting with the spices,
are a pain in the ass.
I wonder if that's really true.
Alright.
This feels pretty authentic.
By the way...
are you my only helper, Lea?
Yes. Lu and Tia said
they're busy with research.
They said something about an
all powerful magical protection talisman.
Whatever.
We can handle it together.
Yes!
First, we start by heating up
the rapeseed oil we extracted.
Then we add in the rabbit meat.
Okay.
While that's cooking,
we grind up all the spices
except for the cumin into a powder.
Is this enough for the meat?
Yeah, looks like it.
Once you've got some color on the meat,
take it off the heat so it doesn't overcook.
Cook the cumin in the leftover bits
and juices from the meat
to bring out the flavor and aroma.
Be careful not to burn them.
It's already starting to smell
like curry at this point.
Wow. I've never smelled
anything like this before.
Next, we need to focus on sautéing
the finely diced onions, ginger, and garlic.
Sauté them without burning them.
Now we add the diced tomatoes,
and we keep on sautéing everything.
Would you like me to take over for a bit?
Yeah, thanks.
Once it's turned into a nice paste,
we can move on.
Spices in. Boom! And we add salt, too.
Cook it a little more.
Then we add in the meat and
boiled soybeans along with some water.
It already looks and smells delicious...
Now we let it simmer
until the meat gets soft.
Do we just need to wait for it now?
Yeah, that's right...
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
What is it?
It's naan!
What's naan?!
It's naan! Naan!
It's naan? Naan?!
I was so focused on the curry
that I forgot about it completely.
Should I just make rice?
No! I want naan with this curry.
How many portions do I need to make?
Me, Lu, Tia...
And if I add in the elves, that makes...
Well, it makes a lot.
It's the same recipe as making regular bread
right up through the part where we let it rise.
The difference is that now we
roll the dough out with a rolling pin.
Okay.
We're going to cook it now, right?
That's right.
You're supposed to cook it
inside of the stove,
but I've seen people cook it using the
outside of a pot before, so we'll try that.
What an interesting plant
this turned out to be.
It doesn't appear to have been poisonous.
What's going on there?
I can smell something appetizing
coming from over there...
And we haven't eaten yet.
Yeah, you're right.
Here's the last one.
Alright.
This should be just about done now.
So this is...
Curry, you said?
It's got a... strange color to it.
I'll need to work up a little courage
to try eating it.
You don't need to be so shy.
I think it probably came out pretty well.
You scoop up the curry with the naan.
That's why we made them flat like this.
Yeah, it's great!
This is real curry.
I can smell all the spices in it.
Oh my. This tingly spiciness
seems like it could become addicting.
The ratio of the spices you use
changes the flavor, right?
This will definitely be worth researching!
Every bite I take makes me
want to eat even more of it!
I'm glad to hear that you all like it.
Well it's got a pretty unique taste,
so if don't really like it then
there's no need to force yourself to...
Um... would you mind
leaving a little for me?
It really works!
Well, it is pretty spicy...
I'm glad the customers liked it,
but now I'm sold out.
This isn't the first time it's happened.
Wow, I'm stuffed.
I definitely want to eat that again sometime.
I've pretty much memorized the recipe!
Let's try changing up how much of
the spices we use next time.
Well they all liked it,
so I guess that's what's important.
But still, eating just a few bites of curry
really makes you hungry.
Farming Life...
in Another...
World
This year's winter started to draw near.
Once the snow starts to fall, we'll spend
most of our days inside the house.
We need to finish our winter preparations
before that happens.
We should be alright with
this much firewood.
Hey, Zabuton!
I brought you something.
When it gets cold outside, Zabuton goes
into hibernation at the top of the tree.
There we go.
I made sure to ask for extra blankets
for the winter ahead of time.
Thanks, we really needed these!
Hey.
Good work.
You too. Good work.
Lea and the elves are going to
keep working on the forge
and some other projects
through the winter.
I'm having Lu and Tia
preserve some food for the winter.
We season the meat,
then smoke it and dry it.
Kuro and the dogs won't be able to
hunt very well during the winter
once it starts to snow.
That's why I want to stock up
on as much as possible.
Hey! Give those back!
Well, I think we'll be okay as far as meat goes.
Right now I'm working on
a way to preserve vegetables.
The vegetables go into the boxes on top.
Then they're covered in a sheet.
And then we cover them with snow.
It's called snow storage.
Vegetables
The bottom boxes are left empty
Empty
and collect water from any snow
that melts to keep the vegetables dry.
I'll try it out as soon as it snows.
Here I go!
I'm going to burn you to ashes!
You're not supposed to burn them.
I'm just messing around.
I wish I could use magic.
Even though I knew there was
no chance it would actually work,
watching them use magic every day
made me feel like I needed to try it
for some reason. I wonder why.
Ignition may be a low level spell,
but you still can't use it
without studying magic.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
You all make it look so easy
that I thought just maybe I could do it.
I tried copying it,
but naturally it didn't work.
The golems Tia summons are considered
difficult to use even among other magic users.
Then doesn't that mean she's pretty amazing
since she can summon a bunch of them at once?
Well yeah, but...
Good job!
I can do a lot of stuff too, you know?
Of course I know.
But still, you guys are all really amazing.
I'm glad to know that I can
rely on you all to help.
All I've been doing is
some garden work and cooking.
What are you talking about?
You're the most amazing one here.
I am?
Living out here like this
for as long as you have...
that's something not just anyone can do.
If you say so.
I do.
No one's been able to do this up until now.
It's just you. You're the only one.
Really?
Yup.
And so, winter had arrived.
The snow began piling up.
I think that should do it.
We were spending more time indoors,
so we needing things to do for fun.
I started with a classic, reversi.
I built a chess set and a mahjong set as well.
Uh...
Reversi?
Yeah.
You play the game with
black and white pieces.
When you surround an opponent's piece
on two sides with your own pieces,
you flip it to your color.
The game ends when the board
completely fills up,
and whichever player has
the most pieces wins.
Those are the only rules.
What a simple game.
Is it really any fun to play?
How shortsighted.
It's the simple design
that allows for complicated strategies
to be developed in this game.
You're absolutely right.
It's amazing that you realized that
just from hearing the rules.
It was nothing.
I challenge you to a game right now, Tia!
As you wish.
After all, you and I have entered a
temporary truce since we started living here.
Indeed. It's time we settled the score.
L-let's try to relax and have some fun.
I'll be white.
That means that Tia gets to move first.
Then I'm black!
Fine...
This is definitely a win for
the white team...
Oh no, my hand slipped!
She's the type that likes to
hit the reset button.
Sorry about that, Tia.
Since we don't know exactly
where the pieces were,
it looks like we'll need to start over.
Wh-what?
Pressing reset doesn't work against her.
Don't you find it embarrassing
to use your magic like that?
Not as embarrassing as
flipping the board because you think
you're about to lose the game.
You haven't learned your lesson, have you?
We're playing best of three!
Fine be me. I accept your challenge.
It looks nice and peaceful over there.
What? Here?
You're right!
You're amazing, Kuro!
He understands the rules?!
They're actually playing the game right.
At a glance, this seems cute.
But I can feel a terrifying energy
coming from them.
I better not challenge
any of them to a game.
Ah, is your game done?
I'm sure I'm not going to lose
to any of the dogs!
Uh, Lu...
I don't think that's a good idea...
Come on, let's play a round.
As I expected, she didn't have the courage
to press the reset button
while playing against Kuro.
Let's see...
Even Kuro shouldn't be able to fully
understand the game of mahjong yet.
It's far too complicated.
This one here?
It might seem a little childish, but...
I'm going to take revenge for Lu now.
Riichi!
Then I call tsumo! No wait, I mean ron!
That's ron for me, too.
At least I think so.
Double ron?!
Wait, the yasume should save...
me!
What?!
I-it's the 13 orphans...
Kuro
Lea
Tia
Hiraku
Hey, isn't this yakuman?
It seemed complicated at first,
but the game is actually pretty simple.
Let's see, Hiraku doesn't have
any points left, so Kuro wins the game!
Kuro, you're number one.
I figured that only playing board games
all day wouldn't be good for our health,
so I built a mini bowling set, too.
Good luck.
I'm definitely not just mad
that I lost at mahjong.
Eight pins. Not bad.
The arsonist and the serial killer
are really hard to take down, aren't they?
The scam artist up front is surprisingly tough, too.
Scam Artist
Arsonist
Serial Killer
These nasty sounding titles are ones
we've given to each of the pins here.
They were just normal pins
I'd carved at first, but...
Why do we want to knock them down?
Lu hit me with that question,
Arsonist
Pirate
Bandit
Scam Artist
Pirate
Bandit
Serial Killer
so I decided the best answer was
"To take out the bad guys."
Got 'em!
I'm up next.
I don't know if it's because
they enjoyed the simplicity of it,
You did it!
but the bowling was a big hit with them.
And so, we spent our winter all together,
nice and cozy inside and playing games.
Those days went by faster
than we thought they would.
The snow melted, and spring came.
What a nice morning.
It's gotten nice and warm outside.
Morning...
Good morning.
What are we going to do today?
Let's see...
I want to finish planting the crops
as soon as we can.
I think it's about time that Zabuton
woke up from her hibernation.
We still have some potatoes left, right?
Yes, I believe so.
Based on the number of taps,
it should be coming from this direction.
It's up there!
Something big is headed here...
Is that... a dragon?!
No, it's a wyvern!
It can't be...
I can feel the soft seasonal winds,
gently on my fingertips
Let's search for what we love
in the clouds floating in the sky
Forget about the hands of the clock for now
Try taking one deep breath
The rainbow-colored scenery
will resonate with my heart
I'm sure any wish I have will come true
Because you're by my side
You make every day feel like a dream
At that warm and kind place
Keep showing me your smiling face forever
Next Time
Episode 6
This Is a Village
Next Time